Guide to the Eugene Sonnenberg Boerner papers, 1894-1968.
Boerner, Eugene Sonnenberg papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Eugene Sonnenberg Boerner papers, 1894-1968.
2639
Eugene Sonnenberg, Boerner 1893-1966.
35 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Legal Documents, Memorabilia, Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Personal and family papers include legal documents; diaries; letters from friends and relatives; memorabilia and papers relating to his student days at the University of Wisconsin and the University of Illinois.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Eugene Sonnenberg Boerner was a rose hybridist, horticulturist, and director of research for the Jackson & Perkins Company, Newark, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Personal and family papers include legal documents; diaries; letters from friends and relatives; memorabilia and papers relating to his student days at the University of Wisconsin and the University of Illinois; financial and other records concerning his model farm "Gene's Landing," on Seneca Lake in New York. Professional papers include foreign and domestic correspondence on rose growing and judging; flower photographs; notes and patent books that describe and picture numerous rose varieties and perennials he developed; domestic and foreign parentage seedling books and hybridizing records; and many lectures, articles, photographs, and notes concerning floriculture and his work for Jackson & Perkins Company.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Boerner, Eugene Sonnenberg,1893-1966.; Jackson & Perkins Company.
Subjects:
Floriculture.; Horticulture.; Roses--Hybridization.; Horticulturists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series 1: Family Papers
Series 2: Personal Papers
Series 3: Business Papers
CONTAINER LIST
- Series 1: Family Papers
  - Genealogical Materials, 1894-1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Paternal and Maternal items, 1895-1915; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Arthur Boerner
    Hemine Boerner
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1907; Herman Boerner; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1907; Herman Boerner; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Robert Boerner
    Alfred Boerner
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1907; Herman Boerner; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Helene Boerner
    Arthur Boerner Sr.
    Arthur Boerner Jr.
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1908; Herman Boerner; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Elsie Cady
    Helene Bcerrer, Arthur Boerner Sr
    Christine Pawlik
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia, 1908; Herman Boerner; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Arthur Boerner Jr
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1909-1913; Herman Boerner; Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1907-1908; School Notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1904-1917; Whitnall Park; Correspondence, drawings, memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1906-1911; Correspondence, notes, memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence & Memorabilia of other Relatives, 1908-1962; News articles, school papers, school memorabilia (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Family Photographs, 1895-1960; Photographs (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Family Photographs, 1895-1960; Photographs (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Series 2: Personal Papers
  - Biographical Essays, 1940-1966; Eugene S. Boerner; Multicopied Biographies (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Biographical articles, 1916-1963; Eugene S. Boerner; Clippings (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Biographical articles, 1964-1969; Eugene S. Boerner; Clippings (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1904-1911; Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 4)
    Herman Boerner
    Anne Boerner
  - Personal Correspondence, 1911; Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1911-1912; Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1912; Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1912; Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Arthur Boerner, Lenore Hughes, C. Pawlik
    Ida Boerner
    Edw. K. Smith
  - Personal Correspondence, 1913-1914; Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1914-1915; Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Helene Boemer
    Eva Marburg
  - Personal Correspondence, 1915-1916; Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1916; Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1917; Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Robert Boener
  - Personal Correspondence, 1917; Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 7)
    World War I - army life
  - Personal Correspondence, 1918-1921; Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1922-1942; Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Bill Boerner
    Harvey Quirin
  - Personal Correspondence, 1942-1949; Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1950-1953; Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Helen Mary Shaw
    Lincoln-Rochester Trust Co.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1954-1955; Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Travel (U.S.)
    Kay Karr, F. Pearson
  - Personal Correspondence, 1956-1959; Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 6)
    F.A. Pearson
  - Personal Correspondence, 1959-1962; Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Cathy Karr
    Helene Schlueter
  - Personal Correspondence, 1963-1964; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Lincoln-Rochester Trust Co.,
    Wertheim & Co.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1964-1965; Jacqueline Kennedy Garden; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1965-1968; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 3)
    Robert Horn
    Dean Charles Palm
    Helene Schleuter
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Eva Mar burg
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 8)
    Helen Boerner
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 9)
    Jean Boerner
  - Personal Correspondence, Undated; Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Christmas Cards, 1907; Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, 1950; Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, 1951-1952; Correspondence (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, 1955-1957; Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, 1959-1960; Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, 1962; Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Christmas Cards, 1963-1965; Correspondence (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Diaries, 1905-1965; Notebooks (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, 1914-1951; Checkstubs (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records, 1951-1966; Checkstubs (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - School Papers, 1904-1910; Notes (Box 20, Folder 1)
    Wisconsin (Cedarburg High School)
  - School Papers, 1910; Notes (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - School Papers, 1910; Tests (Box 20, Folder 3)
    Cedarburg High School
  - School Papers, 1911-1912; Notes (Box 20, Folder 4)
    University of Wisconsin
  - School Papers, University of Wisconsin, 1911-1912; Notes (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - School Papers, University of Wisconsin, 1911-1916; School Records (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - School Papers, University of Illinois, 1916-1917; Notes (Box 23, Folder 3)
    University of Illinois
  - School Papers, University of Illinois, 1915; Notes (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - School papers, University of Illinois, 1915-1917; Notes (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - School papers, University of Illinois, 1915-1917; Notes (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - School papers, University of Illinois, 1915-1917; Notes (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - School papers, University of Illinois, 1915-1917; Memorabilia (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - School papers, University of Illinois, 1915-1917; Memorabilia (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - School papers, University of Illinois, 1915-1917; Memorabilia (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Military Papers, 1918; Notes (Box 23, Folder 4)
    Texas; military training
  - Military Papers, 1918; Notes (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1940-1943; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 1)
    farm labor
    James Brennan
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1943; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1944; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1944; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1944; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 5)
    Margaret Kemper
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1945; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 6)
    Bill Utting
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1945; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1945; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1946; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 9)
    Edward Joy Co.
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1946; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1946; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1947; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1947; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1947; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 14)
    John Kiehle
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1948; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 24, Folder 15)
    Lloyd Ridley
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1948; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1948; James Emerson; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 2)
    Clinton Barnes
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1949; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 3)
    farm labor, wheat growing
    N.Y. Seed Improvement Cooperative Association
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1950; F.L. Stewart; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 4)
    Turnbull Tractors
    N.Y. Certified Seed Growers Coop.
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1951-1952; George Muth; James Brennan; Henry Christensen; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 5)
    U.S. Department of Agriculture
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1953-1954; Henry Christensen; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 6)
    Cattle breeding and marketing, farm labor
    Hillcrest Farms
    Upper Kentland Farms
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1955-1957; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 7)
    Farm equipment, farm labor
    L.F. Beers Co.
    George Muth Co.
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1958-1960; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 8)
    Farm labor, cattle breeding and marketing
    John Rice and Sons
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1960; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 9)
    Farm labor, grape growing, cattle raising and marketing
    Gold Seal Vineyards
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1961; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 10)
    Farm labor
    Utica Mutual Insurance Campany
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1962; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1963; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 12)
    Sears, Roebuck & Co.
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1963; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 13)
    Farm labor, cattle breeding ad marketing
    Hidden River Farms
    Silver Spring Farms
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1964; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1965; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Gene's Landing, Correspondence, 1966-1967; Robert Generaux; Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Gene's Landing, 1949-1952; Frank Van Jeuren; Farm Work Sheets (Box 25, Folder 1)
    Farm Labor
  - Gene's Landing, 1952-1954; Henry Christensen; William Dailey; Farm Work Sheets (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Gene's Landing, 1953-1956; Maurice Babcock; Gerald Bornheimer; Farm Work Sheets (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Gene's Landing, 1958-1959; Roger Don Haese; Farm Work Sheets (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Gene's Landing, 1959; Farm Work Sheets (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Gene's Landing, 1959-1960; Roger Don Haese; Farm Work Sheets (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Gene's Landing, 1960-1961; James Alexander; Neil Anderson; Farm Work Sheets (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Gene's Landing, 1962-1963; Paul Hamilton; Roger Don Haese; Farm Work Sheets (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Gene's Landing, 1963; Bruce Campbell; William King; Farm Work Sheets (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Gene's Landing, 1963-1964; Donald Homer; Mary Homer; Farm Work Sheets (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Gene's Landing, 1957-1962; Farm Work Sheets (Box 26, Folder 11)
    Robert Enos
    Ronald Gage
    Charles Garratt
    Dan Generaux
    George Gifford
    Raymond Gysel
    Robert Hager
    Lloyd Hamilton
    Bernice Hamilton
    Bill Heise
  - Gene's Landing, 1959-1965; Farm Work Sheets (Box 26, Folder 12)
    Bruce Orenshire
    Kenneth Payne
    Forrest Peterson, John Reed
    William Skinner
    Tom Spedding
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1942-1966; Account Books (Box 27)
    Farms and Farming
  - Personal Papers, 1943-1960; Financial Documents (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1950-1966; Farm Inventories (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1943-1961; Correspondence (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1937-1960; Financial Documents (Box 28)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1940-1966; Check Stubs (Box 29)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1949-1959; Check Stubs (Box 30)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1960-1966; Check Stubs (Box 31)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1943-1966; Inventories, Photostats, Tax Statements (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Gene's Landing, Financial Records, 1960-1966; Financial Documents (Box 32, Folder 2)
    Cattle Breeding and Marketing
  - Gene's Landing, 1958-1966; Advertisements (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Gene's Landing, 1946-1966 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Gene's Landing, 1949-1964; Notebook (Box 32)
    Cattle Breeding
  - Photographs E.S. Boerner, Undated; Photographs (Box 33)
  - Photographs Gene's Landing, Undated; Photographs (Box 34)
  - Photographs Gardens and Flowers, Undated; Photographs (Box 35)
  - Photographs Gene's Landing, Undated; Photographs (Box 36)
  - Recipes, 1941-1942; Correspondence (Box 37, Folder 1)
    Rose Recipes and Growing
  - Awards, 1947-1965 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    American Rose Society
    Rochester Bureau of Recreation
    500 Beef Club
    Massachusetts Horticultural Society
  - Awards, 1948-1966 (Box 37)
  - Memorabilia, Undated (Box 38)
    Steamship menus, passport, pocket watch, spoons, pen, etc.
- Series 3: Business Papers
  - General Correspondence and Papers, 1912-1915; Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 1)
    Jackson and Perkins Co.
  - General Correspondence, 1940-1950; Ray Hastings; Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 2)
    Cornell University
    L. Richard Guylay and Associates
    Armstrong Nurseries
  - General Correspondence, 1951-1954; Ralph Dasher; A.M.S. Pridham; Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 3)
    Star Roses
    Stak Brothers Nursery
  - General Correspondence, 1955-1957; Ralph Dasher; Professor Griffith Buck; Correspondence (Box 39, Folder 4)
    Iowa State College
    Swim and Weeks
    American Horticultural Council
  - General Correspondence, 1958-1963; Robert Jordan; Notes (Box 39, Folder 5)
    American Rose Society, rose growing (research), rose judging
  - General Correspondence, 1964; Notes (Box 39, Folder 6)
    Rose Growing (Research)
  - General Correspondence, 1965-1966; Professor Weinard; Fred Turner; Ann Dorner; Notes (Box 39, Folder 7)
    University of Illinois (centennial rose), Jackson & Perkins Co.
  - Foreign Business Correspondence, 1933-1965; Notes (Box 40)
    Domenico Aicardi
    J.S. Baker
    G.A.H. Buisman
    Heinrich Burkhard
    Thomas Carlisle
    A. Couteau
    Marguerite Denoyel
    G. DeRuiter
    Alex Dickson
  - Foreign Business Correspondence, 1933-1965; Notes (Box 41)
    National Rose Society
  - Foreign Business Correspondence, 1932-1958; Notes (Box 42)
    Old Farm Nurseries
    Royal Moerheim Nurseries
  - Foreign Business Correspondence, 1932-1965; Notes (Box 43)
  - Trip Notes, 1939-1965; Notes (Box 43)
  - Trip Notes, 1951-1965; Notes (Box 43)
    Tour Itineraries
  - Flower Notes, 1955-1966; Notes (Box 44)
    Rose growing, rose growing (Arizona), rose growing (California )
  - Flower Notes, 1943-1958; Notes (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Flower Notes, 1953-1965; Notes (Box 45, Folder 2)
    Dictated notes on rose observations at Cornell Rose Gardens and in Springfield, Illinois hospital; germination and hybridizing; rosedust formula, typed conversation with Roland Browne
  - Flower Notes, 1939-1962; Notes (Box 45, Folder 3)
    Flower, flower growing (hybridization)
  - Flower Notes, 1947-1962; Notes (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1947-1967; Notes (Box 45)
    Rose growing (research), rose growing (flower shows)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1956-1963; Notebooks (Box 46)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1930-1965; Notebooks (Box 47)
    Rose growing (domstic seedlings records)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1940-1945; Notebooks (Box 48)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1947-1949; Notebooks (Box 49)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1950-1952; Notebooks (Box 50)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1952-1955; Notebooks (Box 51)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1956-1958; Notebooks (Box 52)
    Rose growing (domestic seedlings records)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1958-1965; Notebooks (Box 53)
    Rose growing (domestic seedling records ), rose, growing (hybridizing records), delphinium growing - (hybridizing records )
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1939-1945; Notebooks (Box 54)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1946-1951; Notebooks (Box 55)
  - Parentage and Seedling Records, 1952-1958; Notebooks (Box 56)
  - Jackson & Perkins, miscellaneous papers, 1950-1958 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    E.S. Boerner
    Charles Perkins
    Clarence Perkins
    R alph Perkins
  - Jackson & Perkins, miscellaneous papers, 1958-1965 (Box 57)
  - Financial Reports
  - Jackson & Perkins, miscellaneous papers, 1924-1966 (Box 58)
  - Correspondence
  - Jackson & Perkins Catalogs, 1941-1963 (Box 59)
  - Catalogs
  - Jackson & Perkins Catalogs, 1940-1966 (Box 60)
  - Catalogs
  - Jackson & Perkins Catalogs, 1946-1966 (Box 61)
  - Catalogs
  - 4: Professional Papers
  - Flower Patent Books, Undated; Patent Books (Box 62)
    Flower growing (plant patent books), rose growing, mum growing
  - Professional Correspondence, 1949; Correspondence (Box 63, Folder 1)
    A l l America Rose Selections
    Fred Edmunds
    Ray Hastings
    Herbert Swim
  - Professional Correspondence, 1949; Correspondence (Box 63, Folder 2)
    L.R. Guylay
    John Armstrong
    E. Dering
  - Professional Correspondence, 1950; Correspondence (Box 63, Folder 3)
    Audry Armstrong (John)
    George Welch
  - Professional Correspondence, 1950-1953; Correspondence (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Professional Organization Reports, 1942-1960; Reports (Box 63)
    National Association of Plant Patent Owners
  - Professional Articles, 1938-1964; Notes (Box 64, Folder 1)
    Lecture at Ohio State University, speeches on roses at various meetings
  - 5: Professional Papers - Aticles and Speeches
  - "The Bases of Heredity", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Heredity
  - "Birth of a Rose", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose Development
  - "Budded Roses", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose Growing
  - "A Call to Arms', 1943; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Victory Gardens
  - "Climbers", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Climbing Roses", 1952; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Degrees of Relationship in Breeding", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Delphiniums", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Delphinium growing (hybridizing)
  - "Europe Befor the War", 1939; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (Pre-war European hybridizing)
  - "Fall Planting", 1943; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Fall Planting of Roses", 1943; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Fall Roses", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "The Floribunda Rose", 1966; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (Floribunda variety)
  - "Floribunda Rose Pinocchio", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Floribunda Roses", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Floribunda Roses", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Floribunda Roses", 1942; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Floribundas, Everybdy's Roses of Today", 1953; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "The Floribundas of the Future", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "The Forgotten Story", 1949 (Box 64)
  - Radio Script
    Rose growing (hybridization)
  - "The Future of the Rose", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (species' names)
  - "Grey Pearl", 1945; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose graving (hybridization)
  - "The Grey Pearl", 1944; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (Grey Pearl Species)
  - "The Home Garden aartet of Roses", 1941; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing
  - "How to Landscape Your Home With Roses", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing, Landscaping
  - "Hybridizer", 1961; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Flower growing (hybridizing)
  - "Hybridizing", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (hybridizing)
  - "Hybridizing at Newark", 1942; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (Newark, New York)
  - "The Hybridizing of Plants*, 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Plant hybridizing
  - "Hybrid Tea Rose Mary Margaret McBride", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "The Inside Story of Jiminy Cricket", 1955; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (Florabunda roses)
  - "Instructions for Applying the Methyl Cellulose Terramycin Paste to Crown Gall", 1956; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    flower growing (disease treatment)
  - "Jackson & Perkins Company", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Let's Do Our Gardening", 1939; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Flower growing
  - "The Life of a Rose", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "The Life History of a New Rose", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "McGredys of Ireland", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Samuel McGredy
    Son Nursery of Ireland
  - "Many Years of Work Are Necessary t o Produce New Roses for You", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Naming New Introductions", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "New and Recent Perrennials", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "Newark, New York Festival of Roses", 1944; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing, Newark (Wayne Co.)
  - "Newark, New York, the Rose Capital of America", 1941; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (flower shows), Newark (Wayne Co.)
  - "The Newer Perennials", 1939; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Flower growing (Perennials)
  - "Newer Perennials for Cut Flowers and Gardens", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Better perennials for florists and gardens, flower growing (Perennials)
  - "New Roses", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Descriptions of new floribundas and hybrid tea roses rose growing (Florabunda variety), rose growing (Tea Roses)
  - "New Roses", 1949; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "New Roses", Undated; Typescript Article (Box 64)
    Rose growing (Floribundas variety), rose growing (hybrid tea variety)
  - "New Roses for 1940", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "New Roses for 1940", 1940; Typescript Article (Box 64)
  - "New Roses for 1942", 1942; Typescript Article (Box 64)